crn.in 2017-12-08

# The Channel Company Privacy Policy | The Channel Company

Home / The Channel Company Privacy Policy

(Revised May 4, 2017)

**Scope**

For purposes of this Privacy Policy (the "Policy"), "The Channel Company" shall refer to both The Channel Company LLC, a Massachusetts limited liability company, and its subsidiary Partner Demand LLC, also a Massachusetts limited liability company.  The Policy covers personal information which you share with The Channel Company as you register for or attend our face-to-face events around the world, visit or participate in any of our websites or online venues which are hosted on servers located in the United States (notably [www.crn.com](http://www.crn.com/); [www.itbestofbreed.com](http://www.itbestofbreed.com/); [wotc.crn.com](http://wotc.crn.com/); [www.thechannelco.com](http://www.thechannelco.com/); [www.partnerdemand.com](http://www.partnerdemand.com/) and [www.iotconnex.com](http://www.iotconnex.com/)), subscribe to any of our print publications, and volunteer or post information, whether through social media or otherwise. We will attempt to post or display a link to this Policy on all forms and online pages to which it applies.

Many of our websites allow you to publish or share content, including personal information which identifies you and/or your company. This Policy will govern how The Channel Company uses the information you provide and what choices you have about its publication.

Each of The Channel Company's lines of business aims to be at the heart of the commercial or professional communities it serves. Our business includes creating opportunities for you to access other companies' information and resources. When we work with other companies to build co-branded web sites, virtual events, sponsored webinars, or in any way that allows you to connect directly with that other company, we will include a link to this Policy and, to the extent it is readily available, to the other company's Privacy Policy as well. Our Policy will govern our collection and use of information about you. We recommend that you read the partner's Policy as well, if applicable, to learn how that company will treat the information you provide.

**Information That Identifies You**

We rely on the information you provide to us – as you register, contact us, participate in surveys, post comments to public areas of and interact with our web sites, respond to our email campaigns, complete applications for award and recognition lists, and participate in webinars or online events. This ordinarily consists of basic contact information – name, company, title, address, telephone number, and email address – but may include other information such as business preferences and affiliations.  We will add information about how you interact with our offerings – your subscriptions, the events you attend, and the like.  We may also supplement with additional data from external sources.

We may work to expand our communities by acquiring names and contact details from other sources that have compiled contact information. This information might be public information or data you provided with necessary permissions. We may also invite you to join our communities via third party social and professional networking sites.

If you download the CRN® Tech News app, The Channel Company uses a third party vendor to collect information about your device.  This data is used only in aggregate for reporting purposes.

**Automatic Data Collection Technologies**

We may also use cookies and common data collection technologies, including web beacons and clear GIFs associated with cookies, on our web pages, in newsletters, and in our email campaigns to collect information both on an aggregate and individual basis.

Some of our web sites use Adobe Flash to provide video content, and the Adobe Flash Player has the ability to separately store information about that particular Flash application. We do not associate this Adobe Flash stored information with you as an individual. Please see the Adobe Flash Player Help page for additional information about controlling the settings of the Adobe Flash Player on your computer.

We gather date, time, certain information about a user's browser and system or device configuration and capabilities, navigation history and IP address for all visitors to our web sites. We use this information for our internal security audit log, for trend analysis and system administration and to gather broad information about our audiences and their geographic locations.

Please see More Information About Cookies (below) for additional details about how we use cookies that identify you, which third party advertisers and advertising networks we allow to serve third party advertising displayed on our sites or to display our ads to you once you have left our web pages, and how to control cookies or their use for serving targeted advertising.

**How We Use Information That Identifies You**

We may use information about you:

  * to provide the services, publications, and information you request -- and to manage your account with us. 
  * to deliver or display content that matches your professional interests and responsibilities. 
  * to contact you with information about and invitations for products and services – ours and other companies' – directed to your professional interests and responsibilities. 
  * to offer you opportunities to connect directly with your peers and with sellers of technology that may be of interest to you. 
  * for another purpose that we tell you about when you give us the information. 

**EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Compliance**

The Channel Company complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework (the "Privacy Shield") as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries.  The Channel Company has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice; Choice; Accountability for Onward Transfer; Security; Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation; Access; and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability.  The Channel Company is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.  If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>. 

To the extent that your data is transferred, The Channel Company exclusively uses third parties that are Privacy Shield-compliant to ensure the integrity and privacy of your data.  In these instances of "onward transfer" of your data, The Channel Company remains potentially liable for subsequent violations of the Privacy Shield.  We shall not be responsible, however, for the compliance of our customers or licensees with Privacy Shield, or their compliance with data privacy laws and regulations of the European Union or any other country.

**Your Choices**

In keeping with one of the Privacy Shield's core principles, Choice, you always have a choice about whether to opt in or opt out, and you maintain control over your data in the following ways:

Deletion of your data, or corrections. Please help us keep your account information up to date. You may update most online registrations by consulting the particular web site itself or visiting a preference page after you have logged on to the site.  Upon request you are entitled to access a copy of your personal data to correct it, or you may instruct us to delete it from our systems.

Connecting directly with other companies for marketing purposes. In addition to providing you with our own editorial content, we offer you the opportunity to access others' branded content and expertise. When you choose to take advantage of that content or expertise, you choose to have your name and contact details transferred directly to that other company. We may put you in direct contact with another company or companies when you choose to:

  * Register for certain registration-only, or "gated" communities. Access to technical resources provided or sponsored by another company is contingent on your agreement that your contact details may be shared with the other company. We may track your interest in that company's content or our own content over time and disclose your interest to that company. 
  * Register for a specific webcast, online event, web site, newsletter, or other offering which is sponsored or co-sponsored by another company. 
  * Register to attend one of our virtual events. We may give your name and contact details to all exhibitors and give the exhibitor whose booths and resources you access a record of your visits and interaction with content from that exhibitor. 
  * Attend one of our face-to-face events. Exhibitors may receive an attendance list for the event. It is up to you, however, to decide whether to leave your business card or allow your RFID-enabled badge to be read by a particular exhibitor – the badges cannot be read remotely. A sponsor of a special, sponsored conference session will also be given information about you if you choose to attend that company's session. Your future interaction with online content from an exhibitor or sponsor to whom you provided your contact data may also be tracked and disclosed to that exhibitor or sponsor. 
  * Submit an application for a published CRN award or recognition list.  To remain eligible for certain awards or lists, you may be required to disclose certain personal data and/or company information. By submitting information requested in an application, you give your permission for this information to be published by The Channel Company on CRN-related media properties and otherwise shared with relevant companies in the IT industry, unless otherwise specified in the award/list application. 

**Making information you provide public**.

We offer websites that allow you to publish content. Many of these blog sites require that you register if you wish to comment. We will publish the user name you provide at registration when you comment. Some sites allow you to create a public profile as well.

Our online event venues also require that you register and allow you to have both public and closed communications with exhibitors and other participants. Information that identifies you will be published or shared according to your choices.

In addition, we may create online membership communities that allow you to create and publish your profile and other information. These communities may provide privacy controls which allow you to choose how much of your profile and other information to make public or to share with others within the community. As a professional, you remain responsible for locating the privacy controls (usually available on the page from which you can edit your profile), understanding how those controls, including default settings, work and protecting the information you provide.

  **Receiving email marketing messages from us**.

You may opt out of our email marketing lists by following the instructions near the footer of our promotional emails. Please note that we have a number of brands and products, and therefore often allow you to opt out selectively. To remove a specific email address from all email marketing from The Channel Company, you may send a request to [privacyrequests@thechannelcompany.com](mailto:privacyrequests@thechannelcompany.com).

**More Information about Cookies**

You also have certain choices about cookies:

We place cookies that identify you, or allow third parties to do so on our behalf, for the following purposes:

  * to recognize you automatically when you return to a gated community. 
  * to understand your interests in content, both our own content and that of other companies, on or across our web sites. 
  * to control access to gated online events including webinars and virtual events. 
  * to make an automated record of your interests within a virtual event. 
  * to manage and follow up on email campaigns. 

You may use the tools in your browser to decline, disable, or delete any cookies. You will still be able to log on to a gated community if you decline or delete our persistent cookie that enables automatic recognition. If you disable the session cookie for our gated sites you may remain on the site but you will not be able to access (download) any gated content. You must accept the session cookie used to manage access to registration-only online events for the duration of your participation in the event.

Third party advertising cookies. We allow other companies to serve ads on our web pages. We do not control their use of cookies or other data collection technologies or practices.

The Channel Company currently allows the following third party ad servers to serve ads on our web pages: TRUSTe and Google AdSense. Some companies offer additional choices about your preferences. Please visit each of their web sites for more information about the technologies they use and their privacy practices.

Many of the third party ad serving companies that serve ads to our web sites are members of the Network Advertising Initiative and/or the Digital Advertising Alliance. The NAI offers useful information about ad networks and a single place to turn off targeted ad serving from any of its member companies: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>.

The Channel Company further adheres to the data privacy principles set forth in the Interactive Advertising Bureau/American Association of Advertising Agencies' Standard Terms and Conditions version 3.0.

We may amend or modify the list of Third Party Advertisers from time to time without changing the effective date of the Policy itself. We urge you to check this section regularly for any modifications.

**Disclosure of Information about You**

We reserve the right to disclose information about you to third parties in certain circumstances: to vendors that work on our behalf, to entities that present valid legal process, to protect human safety or our networks or property, or as part of a corporate merger or sale of our business assets.

Please note that we may be required to disclose an individual's personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

**Data Security**

We collect and process information on servers around the world. We use reasonable administrative, technical, and physical safeguards to protect personal information against theft, loss, or misuse. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or storage can be guaranteed to be 100 percent secure. As a result, while we strive to protect information about you and your professional interests, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you submit to us. You remain responsible for protecting your user name and passwords and for the security of information in transit to us over the Internet.

This Privacy Policy covers how we use information you provide. We cannot control how others may use information you may make public on our sites, for example, on professional networking sites or sites inviting user-generated content, in forums, at virtual events, or user-generated blogs.

Please note that virtual events may automatically display certain information about you to other participants in the event. We cannot control how other participants use that displayed information, so please take a moment to make sure you understand how a particular virtual event works and what information you are choosing to share within that particular environment.

**Changes**

We will post and date any changes to this Privacy Policy. Please check here periodically. Your continued use of our products and services covered by this Policy constitutes your consent to the practices in place at the time of your use.

**Dispute Resolution**

In compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield, The Channel Company commits to resolve complaints free of charge about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information.  European Union individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Adam Gusman, Senior Corporate Counsel, at: [privacyrequests@thechannelcompany.com](mailto:privacyrequests@thechannelcompany.com)   Tel. +00 (508) 416-1142; Fax +00 (508) 861-0116.  Or by mail to:  The Channel Company, One Research Drive, Suite 400B, Attn: Corporate Counsel, Westborough, MA 01581, USA.

The Channel Company has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles to BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, a non-profit alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States and operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit [www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/](http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/) for more information and to file a complaint.

Please note that if your complaint is not resolved through these channels, under limited circumstances, a binding arbitration option may be available before a Privacy Shield Panel.

  *
